舰长日志，星历2821.5
Captain's log, stardate 2821.5.
运送医疗补给前往玛克斯3号星的途中
En route to Makus III with a cargo of medical supplies.
我们的航线将经过紫312星体
Our course leads us past Murasaki 312,
类星球构造，晦暗不明，情况不定
a quasar-like formation. Vague, undefined,
这是个宝贵的科学调查机会
a priceless opportunity for scientific investigation.
同时登舰的还有负责监督医药运输到
On board is Galactic High Commissioner Ferris,
玛克斯3号星的银河系高级专员菲利斯
overseeing the delivery of the medicines to Makus III.
舰长呼叫伽利略号穿梭机，史波克先生，待命
Captain to shuttlecraft Galileo. Stand by, Mr. Spock.
容我提醒你，舰长，我强烈反对此次延误
I remind you, captain, I'm entirely opposed to this delay.
你的任务是将这些紧急医用物资
Your mission is to get those emergency medical supplies
按时送往玛克斯3号星的新巴黎殖民地
to Makus III in time for their transfer to the New Paris colonies.
没问题，专员先生
No problem, commissioner.
我也真诚地提醒你
And may I remind you
我有长期指令，无论在何时遇到
that I have standing orders to investigate all quasars
所有类星体及类星体现象，都要去研究它
and quasar-like phenomena wherever they may be encountered.
并且
Besides...
…去玛克斯只要三天
...it's three days to Makus.
而五天后才在集结地会合
And the rendezvous doesn't take place for five.
我不喜欢碰运气
I don't like to take chances.
新巴黎上瘟疫已经失控
The plague is out of control on New Paris.
我们必须准时送达这些药品
We must get those drugs there on time.
没问题
No problem.
舰长呼叫伽利略号
Captain to Galileo.
所有系统就绪，准备发射
All systems cleared for takeoff.
启动，所有仪器启动，一切读数正常
Power up. All instruments activated. All readings normal.
- 一切就绪 - 发射穿梭机
- All go. - Launch shuttlecraft.
读数正常
Readings normal.
加速平稳
Acceleration normal.
- 一级分离正常 - 位置？
- Phase one separation normal. - Position?
3.7
3.7.
- 长官，我… - 想清楚说什么，拉蒂莫先生
- Sir, l-- - Make up your mind, Mr. Latimer.
- 长官，指示器读数飚了 - 意料之中，史波克先生
- Sir, this indicator's gone crazy. - That's to be expected, Mr. Spock.
类星体本就极端混乱
Quasars are extremely disruptive.
只是我们不知道有多混乱
Just how much, we don't know.
相当混乱，博马先生
Considerably, Mr. Boma.
史波克先生，辐射在增强
Mr. Spock, radiation is increasing.
停止前进，拉蒂莫先生
Stop forward momentum, Mr. Latimer.
不行长官，按了没用
I can't, sir. Nothing happens.
伽利略号呼叫进取号
Galileo to Enterprise.
伽利略号呼叫进取号，请回答
Galileo to Enterprise. Come in, please.
有离子干扰，史波克先生
Ionic interference, Mr. Spock.
我们正被拉扯进类星体
We're being drawn right into it.
伽利略号呼叫进取号
Galileo to Enterprise. Galileo to Enterprise.
我们失控了，正被径直吸进紫312
We are out of control, being pulled directly into the heart of Murasaki 312.
外壳受到严重辐射损害
Being hit by violent radiation on outer hull.
航向3.25
Course 3.25.
- 听出什么吗？ - 信号不清晰，舰长
- Anything at all? - Nothing clear, captain.
好像说了什么正被拉离航向
Just a few words about being pulled off course.
- 帮我定位伽利略号 - 扫描器一片空白，舰长
- Try and get me a fix on the Galileo. - Scanners are blank, captain.
我们收到一大串前所未见的读数
We're getting a mass of readings I've never seen before.
一切都乱了套
Nothing makes sense.
负离子浓度
Negative ionic concentration,
1.64*10的9次方
1.64 times ten to the ninth power metres.
辐射波长，370埃
Radiation wavelength, 370 angstroms.
整频段充斥谐波
Harmonics upward along entire spectrum.
怎么了，舰长
What is it, captain?
这鬼东西离子化了整个区域
That thing out there has ionized this complete sector.
我们的仪器全部失灵
None of our instruments work.
至少四个完整的太阳系紧密相连
At least four complete solar systems in the immediate vicinity,
而在那某个地方，有艘24英尺的
and out there somewhere a 24-foot shuttlecraft,
偏离航向，失去控制
off course, out of control.
找他们犹如大海捞针
Finding a needle in a haystack would be child's play.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages Of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢的航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：疯狂小骨头，傻得雷，sholto
校对：心痕依，诸星龟龟，Micezhang
第一季第16集
伽利略号七勇士
船长日志，星历2821.7
Captain's log, stardate 2821.7.
被称之为“紫312”星体的电磁现象犹如
The electromagnetic phenomenon known as Murasaki 312
一道怒光旋转在太空
whirls like some angry blight in space,
它扣紧我们的心弦，提醒我们
a depressive reminder that seven of our shipmates
有7名船员仍然渺无音讯
still have not been heard from.
祸不单行，电磁已经使我们的
Equally bad, the effect has rendered
搜寻系统失灵
our normal searching systems useless.
没有搜寻系统，我们无助而迷茫
Without them, we are blind and almost helpless.
一开始我就反对这计划
I was opposed to this from the very beginning.
前往玛克斯3号的飞行任务有最高优先级
Our flight to Makus III is of the very highest priority.
我知道，专员先生
I'm aware of that, commissioner.
同时，我也有必须执行的科学职责
At the same time, I have scientific duties
而探索紫星云现象也是其中之一
I must perform, and investigating the Murasaki Effect is one of them.
对，但是你失去了你的船员
Yes, but you've lost your crew.
- 我们有两天去找他们 - 两天？
- We have two days to find them. - Two days?
在那里面？两天？
In all that? Two days?
你要我怎么做，直接走人，抛下他们？
What would you have me do? Turn around and leave them there?
你一开始就不应该派他们去
You shouldn't have sent them out in the first place.
舰长，在这太阳系里有颗行星
Captain, there's one planet in this solar system
适合人类生存
capable of sustaining human life.
M型，有氧气，氮气，被列作金牛座2号星
It's type-M, oxygen, nitrogen, and it's listed as Taurus II.
尚未被勘探
It's unexplored.
据我们运作异常的仪器显示
As far as we can determine with our equipment malfunction,
它就在紫星云现象的风眼
it's just about dead centre of the Murasaki Effect.
- 谢谢，苏鲁 - 舰长
- Thank you. Mr. Sulu. - Yes, sir
- 前往金牛座二号星 - 遵命，长官
- Set course for Taurus II. - Aye, aye, sir.
- 你还好吗？ - 是的
- You all right? - Yeah.
史考特？博马？
Scotty? Boma?
这才叫探险啊
Now, that's what I call a ride.
- 文书？ - 没事
- Yeoman? - Yeah.
脑袋稍微被撞一下
Just got a little bump on the head.
- 起来，坐下 - 谢谢
- Up. Sit down. - Thank you.
- 怎么了？ - 不确定
- What happened? - I can't be sure.
大概是磁力的效应
But I'd say that the magnetic potential of the effect was--
谢谢
Thank you.
使得我们加速时
Was such that, as we gathered speed,
加速度顿时以几何级数增长
it was multiplied geometrically.
我们被直接射到了紫星云中心
And we were simply shot into the centre of the effect.
像个抛射体
Well, like a projectile.
你说的有道理，博马
I'd say your evaluation is reasonable, Mr. Boma.
真是一团糟
What a mess.
形象的描述修不好损坏的电路，史考特先生
Picturesque descriptions will not mend broken circuits, Mr. Scott.
我想你清楚工作在等着你了
I think you'll find your work is cut out for you.
伽利略号呼叫进取号，请回答
Galileo to Enterprise. Galileo to Enterprise. Come in, please.
你真指望会有人回应吗？
You don't really expect to get an answer, do you?
我没指望任何事，史考特先生
I expect nothing, Mr. Scott.
这是唯一符合逻辑的做法，尝试任何可能性
It is merely logical to try all the alternatives.
麦考伊医生，请告诉我大气压参数
Dr. McCoy, a reading on the atmosphere, please.
氧气部分压强，70毫米汞柱
Partial pressure of oxygen, 70 millimetres of mercury.
氮气，140
Nitrogen, 140.
只要不赛跑的话，还是可以呼吸的
Breathable, if you're not running in competition.
陈述事实就好，医生
Just the facts, doctor.
氩、氖、氪量均在可接受范围
Traces of argon, neon, krypton, all in acceptable quantities.
不过，我不推荐夏天在这度假
However, I wouldn't recommend this place as a summer resort.
谢谢你的意见，我会记下的
Thank you for your opinion. It will be duly noted.
- 你在记录吗，文书？ - 当然，史波克先生
- You're recording this, yeoman? - Of course, Mr. Spock.
史考特先生，请对损坏做个评估
All right. Mr. Scott, if you'll make a survey of damage, please.
- 真有逻辑 - 先生们
- Logical. - Gentlemen,
我想我们应该出去
I think we should move outside and make room
好让史考特完成他的工作
for Mr. Scott to do his work.
拉蒂莫，盖塔诺，你们带好武器
Mr. Latimer, Mr. Gaetano, you'll arm yourselves,
侦查该区域，与飞船保持可视距离
scout out the area, keeping in visual contact with the ship.
遵命长官
Aye, aye, sir.
你觉得我们联系到进取号的概率有多大？
What do you think our chances are of contacting the Enterprise?
以目前的情况，几乎不可能
Under present conditions, extremely poor.
不过他们会来找我们的
But they'll be looking for us.
如果离子化作用范围如我所猜的一样，医生
If the ionization effect is as widespread as I believe it is, doctor,
他们将无法用仪器找我们了
they'll be searching for us without instrumentation.
只能用肉眼
By visual contact only.
同时，这个星球还很大
On those terms, this is a very large planet.
你觉得他们找不到我们？
Then you don't think they'll find us?
只要我们在陆地上，就悬了
Not as long as we're grounded.
我们可能在这里待很久，医生
We may be here for a very long time, doctor.
没有回音，舰长
Nothing, captain.
- 苏鲁 - 什么，舰长？
- Mr. Sulu. - Yes, captain?
- 扫描仪上显示什么了吗？ - 无法正常工作，长官
- Anything on your scanners? - Totally inoperative, sir.
没有任何读数
- No readings at all. - Have you tried
- 试过增加辅助电源吗？ - 是的，长官，没变化
- tying into the auxiliary power? - Yes, sir. No change.
舰长呼叫传送室
Transporter Room. This is the captain speaking.
传送器能传送了吗？
Are the transporters beaming up yet?
还有些问题，舰长
Not 1 00 percent, captain.
我们传输了一些惰性材料
We beamed down some inert material, but it came back
不过它们回来时七零八落
in a dissociated condition.
我们现在还不敢传送人
We wouldn't dare try it with people.
谢谢
Thank you.
舰长呼叫飞行甲板
This is the captain speaking.
准备立即发射哥伦布号
Flight deck, prepare Columbus for immediate exit
对行星表面进行搜索
for a search of the planet's surface.
联系苏鲁以获取坐标，谢谢
Correlate coordinates with Mr. Sulu. Thank you.
有反应吗，乌乎拉？
Anything, Uhura?
所有不同波长的信号都被离子化了，长官
All wavelengths dominated by ionization effect, sir.
信号被阻断了，也无法接收
Transmission is blocked, reception impossible.
舰长
Well, captain...
我们可以持续搜寻到星历2823.8，专员
We have until 2823.8 to continue the search, commissioner.
你真以为你有这么好运气？
You don't really think you'll have any luck, do you?
这些人是我的朋友和船员
Look, these people are my friends and my shipmates.
我坚持此舰继续搜索
I intend to continue this ship's search for them
不到最后一刻不罢休
until the last possible moment.
那好吧，舰长
Very well, captain.
不过一秒都不得超过那个期限
But not one second beyond that moment.
明白吗？
Is that clear?
如果还不清楚，我建议你看看规章第19册，433章，12段…
If it isn't, I suggest you look at book 19, section 433, paragraph 12--
我很熟悉这些条例，专员
I'm familiar with the regulations, commissioner.
我也非常清楚您的权力
I know all about your authority.
发射哥伦布号穿梭机
Launch shuttlecraft Columbus.
好吧，对于现状我无话可说
Well, I can't say much for the circumstances,
不过至少你的机会来了
but at least it's your big chance.
- 我的机会？什么机会？医生？ - 指挥权啊
- My big chance? For what, doctor? - Command.
我知道，史波克先生
Oh, I know you, Mr. Spock.
你从没说，但是你一直认为
You've never voiced it, but you've always thought that logic
逻辑是指挥最好的基础，对吧？
was the best basis on which to build command. Am I right?
我是个讲逻辑的人，医生
I am a logical man, doctor.
这次要脱离险境可不只靠逻辑
Well, it'll take more than logic to get us out of this.
也许吧，医生，可我知道没有更好的办法了
Perhaps, doctor, but I know of no better way to begin.
我知道甚至在这样的情况下
I realise that command does have its fascinations,
指挥权也有其独特的魅力
even under circumstances such as these.
不过我既不享受指挥
But I neither enjoy the idea of command,
也不害怕指挥
nor am I frightened of it.
但就有这么个概念
It simply exists.
我只会依着我的逻辑走
And I will do whatever logically needs to be done.
失陪了
Excuse me.
- 情况不妙，史波克先生 - 怎么了？
- Very bad, Mr. Spock. - In what way?
我们损失了大量燃料
We've lost a great deal of fuel.
我们没可能达到逃逸速度
We have no chance at all to reach escape velocity.
如果我们要进入环绕轨道，就必须减轻
And if we ever hope to make orbit, we'll have to lighten our load
至少500磅载重量
by at least 500 pounds.
也就是三名成人重量
The weight of three grown men.
可以那么说
You could put it that way.
或者说同样重量的设备
Or the equivalent weight in equipment.
麦考伊医生，除非极个别例外
Dr. McCoy, with very few exceptions, we use virtually every piece
我们要用船上的每件设备来进入轨道
of equipment aboard this craft in attaining orbit.
除了乘客外，没有额外的重量
There is very little excess weight, except among the passengers.
你是指我们有三个人要留在这星球上
You mean three of us must stay behind.
如果情况没有显著改观的话，是的
Unless the situation changes radically, yes.
谁来选人呢？
And who is to choose?
作为指挥官，我会选定人
As commanding officer, the choice will be mine.
你不会想抽签吧？
You wouldn't be interested in drawing lots?
很奇怪的提案，博马先生，但我认为
A very quaint idea, Mr. Boma, but I do believe I’m better qualified
由我来选比随机选人更有效
to make the selection than any random drawing of lots.
那好，史波克先生，谁？
All right, Mr. Spock, who?
我的选择会是依从逻辑的
My choice will be a logical one,
逻辑选择
arrived at through logical means.
史波克，生死攸关没有所谓逻辑
Mr. Spock, life and death are seldom logical.
不过达到目标必须理智，医生
But attaining a desired goal always is, doctor.
先生们，我建议我们出去
Now, gentlemen, I suggest we move outside
对船体做一个彻查
to make a further examination of the hull
以防我们忽略了任何小损伤
in the event we've overlooked any minor damage.
要说有什么问题被忽略的话
If any minor damage was overlooked,
大概是他脑子出问题了吧
it was when they put his head together.
不是他脑袋，博马先生
Not his head, Mr. Boma.
是他的心
His heart.
什么东西？
What is it?
不知道，从上面发出的声音
I don't know. It’s from up there.
不，是从后面发出的
No, it's from back there.
我们周围到处都是这声音
It's everywhere. It's all around us.
我们快离开这
Let's get out of here.
走，博马
Come on, Boma.
什么东西？
What was it?
有个很大很恐怖的东西
Something huge, terrible.
在上面，我想我打中它了
Up there. I think I hit it.
你看到那是什么东西了吗？
Did you see what it was?
隐隐约约，像只巨型猩猩
Vaguely. It was like a giant ape.
可怜的拉蒂莫
Poor Latimer.
至少他没受多少痛苦
Well, at least it was quick for him.
我们会没事的
We'll get off all right.
- 没东西 - 我说了，有
- Nothing there. - I tell you, there was.
- 我不怀疑你说的 - 那里肯定有什么东西在
- I don't doubt your word. - Well, there must be something.
我发誓我打中它了
I swear I hit it.
- 伏尔松之矛 - 什么？
- Folsom point. - Sir?
我说这个十分像西历1925年
This. A remarkable resemblance to the Folsom point,
在美国北部新墨西哥州
discovered 1925, Old World calendar.
发现的伏尔松之茅
New Mexico, North America.
我觉得矛柄更原始些
A bit more crude about the shaft, I believe.
十分笨重
Not very efficient.
“十分笨重”，你就想说这个？
"Not very efficient." Is that all you have to say?
我说错了吗，博马先生
Am I in error, Mr. Boma?
你说的永远对，行了吧
You, err? Impossible.
那怎么了，博马先生
Then what, Mr. Boma?
有个人死在这儿
There's a man lying there dead,
你却在讨论石矛？
and you talk about stone spears.
那拉蒂莫怎么办？
What about Latimer?
我对逝者的关心并不能让他复生，博马先生
My concern for the dead will not bring him back to life, Mr. Boma.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock,
以效率标准而言
in the interest of efficiency,
我觉得不应该把他的尸体留在这儿
I don't think we should leave his body here.
把他带回飞船应该不会影响修理工作
Bringing him back to the ship should not interfere with our repair efforts.
- 如果你们需要帮手，我可以… - 我们来就行
- If you need assistance, I’ll-- - We'll do it.
帮我抬一下拉蒂莫好吗？
Give me a hand with Latimer, will you?
舰长日志，星历2822.3
Captain's log, stardate 2822.3.
我们仍在搜寻
We continue to search,
但每过一秒我都愈发抵挡不了
but I find it more difficult each moment
徒劳无功的窒息感
to ward off a sense of utter futility
和巨大的失落感
and great loss.
舰长，哥伦比亚号已经从
Captain, the Columbus has returned
搜寻区域779-X至534-M返回，没有结果
from searching quadrant 779-X by 534-M. Results negative.
让他们去下一个搜寻区域
Have them proceed to the next quadrant.
传感器那边有消息吗？
Any word from Engineering on our sensors?
还在修理中，长官，还不能用
They're working on them, sir. Still inoperable.
传送器呢？
What about the transporters?
- 报告依然是不安全 - 谢谢，上尉
- They're still reported unsafe. - Thank you, lieutenant.
- 舰长 - 什么事，专员先生？
- Captain. - Yes, commissioner?
抛弃你的手下，这想法我并不喜欢
I don't relish the thought of abandoning your crewmen out there.
- 但是我必须提醒你… - 我还没忘呢，专员先生
- However, I must remind you-- - I haven't forgotten, commissioner.
时间不多了
You're running out of time.
我牢记在心，专员先生
I haven't forgotten that, commissioner.
我是舰长，试试过载传送器的功率
This is the captain. Try using overload power on the transporters.
- 必须得让它们运转起来 - 收到，舰长
- We've got to get them working. - Aye, aye, captain.
乌乎拉，命令哥伦比亚号从现在开始
Uhura, order the Columbus to open its course two degrees
每一圈探测范围加大两度
on every lap from now on.
但是，舰长，两度意味着
But, captain, two degrees means you'll be overlooking
每搜索一圈都会漏掉十几英里
more than a dozen terrestrial miles on each search loop.
同时这也意味着我们可以争取
It also means we have a fighting chance
搜寻完这颗星球的大部分区域
to cover the majority of the planet's surface.
留神操舵吧，苏鲁先生
Mind your helm, Mr. Sulu.
遵命，长官
Yes, sir.
还剩24小时，舰长
Twenty-four more hours, captain.
也许你可以通过主进气阀
Perhaps if you were to channel the second auxiliary tank
开第二辅助槽
through the primary intake valve.
太纤细了，也许不能承受那样的压力
It's too delicate. It may not be able to take the pressure as it is.
这应该能给我们省至少50磅，史波克先生
This should save us at least 50 pounds, Mr. Spock.
很好，医生
Excellent, doctor.
我们应该还能再凑个100磅
We should be able to scrape up another 100 pounds.
这样我们还是超重至少150磅
Which would still leave us at least 150 pounds overweight.
我不敢相信你是真的在考虑丢下谁
I can't believe you're serious about leaving someone behind.
现在不管外边是什么，我们都…
Now, whatever it is out there that we--
牺牲一条命比六条更合理，医生
It is more rational to sacrifice one life than six, doctor.
我没在讨论合理性
I'm not talking about rationality.
那你最好开始考虑
You might be wise to start.
- 史波克先生，一切就绪了 - 什么事情？
- Mr. Spock, we're ready. - For what?
拉蒂莫的葬礼
The services for Latimer.
博马先生，我们在和时间赛跑
Mr. Boma, we're working against time.
他死了，体面的葬礼是他应得的
The man's dead. He deserves a decent burial.
你是队长，几句话就好
You're the captain. A few words.
医生，可能你知道在这种场合下的致辞
Doctor, perhaps you know the correct words for such an occasion.
史波克先生，那应该是你的职责
Mr. Spock, that's your place.
我的职责在这里，劳驾了，医生
My place is here, if you please, doctor.
好吧，我们都可能葬身于此
Now, look. We may all die here.
至少让我们死得像个人类，而不是机器
At least let us die like men, not machines.
要事优先
By dealing with first things first,
我希望提升我们的生存机会
I hope to increase our chances of staying alive.
- 好了，史考特先生？ - 帮我个忙
- Well, Mr. Scott? - If you'll give me a hand
拿个导管…
with this conduit...
压力在下降
The pressure's dropping.
- 前功尽弃了 - 怎么了？
- We're losing everything. - What happened?
一根电线断了
One of the lines gave.
通过的气体和
The strain of coming through the atmosphere
我们想分流时增加的负载张力
and the added load when we tried to bypass.
好了，这下可好了
Yeah, that's done it.
我们没有燃料了
We have no fuel.
好吧，这似乎解决了我们要留下谁的问题
Well, it would seem to solve the problem of who to leave behind.
考虑一下备选方案，史考特先生
Consider the alternatives, Mr. Scott.
没有燃料了，还有什么备选方案？
We have no fuel. What alternatives?
史考特先生，备选方案总是有的
Mr. Scott, there are always alternatives.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
外边有情况
Something's happening outside.
那高灵敏度的耳朵怎么看，史波克先生？
What do those super-sensitive ears make of that, Mr. Spock?
木头
Wood,
在一种皮革上摩擦
rubbing on some kind of leather.
他们蓄势待发，要攻过来了
They're getting ready. They'll attack.
不一定
Not necessarily.
也许只是部落仪式，如果是部落文明的话
It could be a simple tribal rite, assuming a tribal culture.
没到部落文明，他们的工具太原始了
Not a tribal culture. Their artefacts are too primitive.
更像是一种松散的联盟
More likely a loose association of some sort.
- 如果我们能更了解他们… - 了解的已经足够多了
- If we knew more about them-- - We know enough.
如果他们是部落，就会有集体感，我们能利用这一点
If they're tribal, they'll have a sense of unity, and we can use that.
- 如何利用呢，博马先生？ - 给他们一记重拳
- How, Mr. Boma? - By hitting them hard.
打他们个鼻青脸肿，这样他们要攻击就得三思而后行
Give them a bloody nose. Make them think twice about attacking us.
对，我同意
Yes, I agree.
如果我们袖手旁观，没有动作
If we stand by and do nothing,
就相当于给他们发邀请函下来鱼肉我们
we're just giving them an invitation to come down and slaughter us.
我总是惊愕于你们地球人
I'm frequently appalled by the low regard
将生命看得如此之轻
you earthmen have for life.
我们只是想法实际而已
Well, we're practical about it.
好吧，我提议先下手为强
Now, I say we hit them before they hit us.
- 博马先生？ - 完全同意
- Mr. Boma? - Absolutely.
- 麦考伊医生？ - 听着很合理
- Dr. McCoy? - Seems logical to me.
的确是
It does indeed.
我看来也很合理
It seems logical to me also.
- 但是对生命一视同仁… - 少数服从…
- But to take life indiscriminately... - The majority--
我对多数人的意见可没兴趣，盖塔诺先生
I'm not interested in the opinion of the majority, Mr. Gaetano.
每个部分都要权衡
The components must be weighed.
对自己的危险，还有对其他生命形式的责任
Our dangers to ourselves as well as our duties to other life forms.
不论是否友善
Friendly or not.
- 还有第三条路 - 可能会害死我们
- There's a third course. - That could get us killed.
- 我不这么认为，麦考伊医生 - 什么吩咐？
- I think not. Dr. McCoy. - Yes?
你和米尔斯文书回飞船上去
You and Yeoman Mears return to the ship.
尽一切可能帮助史考特先生
Assist Mr. Scott in any way possible.
- 我们很快回来 - 好的
- We'll be back shortly. - Right.
先生们
Gentlemen,
你们要严格遵守我的命令
you'll follow my orders to the letter,
只有在我的指示下才能开火
firing only when so instructed
对象只能是我指定的目标
and at my designated targets.
- 你讲吧 - 我们开火只是为了威慑，盖塔诺先生
- Now you're talking. - We'll fire to frighten, Mr. Gaetano.
不是杀戮
Not to kill.
哦，天…
Oh, for the--
- 你也看见了他们怎么对拉蒂莫的 - 我是领导，盖塔诺先生
- You saw what they did to Latimer. - I am in command, Mr. Gaetano.
指令和责任都是我的
The orders and the responsibility will be mine.
跟我来
Follow me.
这些雾，我…
The mists, l...
- 我看不见它们 - 我能听见
- I can't see them. - I hear them.
他们就在我们正前方
They're directly ahead of us.
应该有好几个
Several, I believe.
你们把相位枪对准2点钟和10点钟方向
You direct your phasers to 2 o'clock and to 10 o'clock.
- 我觉得应该直接击毙 - 对，我懂
- I say we hit them dead on. - Yes, I know.
还好下达命令的人是我
But fortunately I'm giving the orders.
请瞄准，我给出信号的时候开火
Take aim, please, and fire when I give the signal.
开火
Fire.
停火
Cease fire.
再来骚扰我们之前他们应该三思了
They should think twice before bothering us again.
- 我还是觉得应该击毙他们 - 没必要
- I still say we should've killed them. - It was not necessary.
该做的事就交给恐惧来做吧
Fear will do for us what needs to be done.
博马先生，和我一起回伽利略号
Mr. Boma, return with me to the Galileo.
盖塔诺先生，你留在这儿站岗
Mr. Gaetano, you remain on guard here.
和飞船保持联络
Keep in contact with the ship.
- 找到他们了吗？ - 嗯，找到了
- Did you find them? - Yes, we found them,
他们不会再来骚扰我们了
and they won't bother us again.
希望如此，史考特有主意了
I hope not. Scotty has an idea.
很危险，但也许能行
It's dangerous, but it might work.
说吧，史考特先生
Go, Mr. Scott.
我可以让主反应器重新运转
I can adjust the main reactor to function
用替代的燃料就行
with a substitute fuel supply.
这主意很好，但我们没有替代的燃料
That's all very well, but we don't have a substitute supply.
我们有，相位枪就是
Aye, we do. Our phasers.
我可以调一下，然后用它们的能量
I can adapt them and use their energy.
会花点时间，但能行
It'll take time, but it's possible.
问题是，这些枪正好是我们唯一的防身武器
Trouble is, they happen to be our only defence.
它们似乎同时也是我们仅存的希望了
They would also seem to be our only hope.
对
Aye.
文书，你的枪
Yeoman, your phaser.
可是万一那些东西又攻过来了呢？
But what if the creatures attack again?
至少几小时以内，他们不会进攻的
They won't attack for at least several hours.
到那时候，如果走运的话，我们已经走了
By then, with luck, we'll be gone.
如果我能充满的话，我们应该可以全员进入轨道
If I can get a full load, we should be able to achieve orbit with all hands.
并不是说我们能坚持很长时间
Not that we can maintain it long.
我们没必要坚持很长时间，史考特先生
We don't have to maintain it very long, Mr. Scott.
24小时之内，进取号就不得不放弃搜寻
In less than 24 hours, the Enterprise will be forced to abandon its search
以奔赴集结地
in order to make a rendezvous.
在那之后如果我们不能维持在轨道上
If we can't maintain orbit after that time,
结果也不会有差别
it won't make any difference.
不管是在衰减轨道上烧死，还是在这星球表面死去
If we burn up in a decaying orbit or die here on the planet's surface,
都是难逃一死
we shall surely die.
医生，你的枪
Doctor, your phaser.
- 去工作吧，史考特先生 - 遵命，长官
- Go to work, Mr. Scott. - Aye, aye, sir.
它们顺利回归了，长官
They came back all right, sir.
我认为传送器现在能安全传送人类了
In my opinion, the transporters are now safe for human transport.
很好
Good.
我是舰长
This is the captain.
一，二，三号登陆队，来传送室报到
Landing parties one, two and three, report to Transporter Room
马上传送至星球表面
for immediate beaming-down to surface of the planet.
军械状态1-A
Ordnance condition 1-A.
舰长，这星球很大
Captain, it's a big planet.
我们的登陆队找到什么全凭运气
It'll be sheer luck if our landing parties find anything.
我靠的就是运气，上尉
I'm depending on luck, lieutenant.
这差不多是我们现在唯一有用的东西了
It's almost the only tool we have that'll work now.
请把枪带回去给史考特先生转换，医生
Take this back to Mr. Scott for conversion, please, doctor.
没人知道盖塔诺身上发生了什么事
Nobody knows what's happened to Gaetano,
而你却若无其事地把他的枪拿走了
and you hand over his phaser like nothing's happened at all.
把这把枪也给史考特先生，以防万一我回不去
And give this to Mr. Scott in the event I don't return.
你这是去哪儿？
And just where are you going?
对于盖塔诺先生的遭遇
I have a certain scientific curiosity
我有一种学术上的好奇心
about what's become of Mr. Gaetano.
请回飞船上去
Return to the ship, please.
我不明白
I don't know.
他会提着项上人头去寻找盖塔诺
He'll risk his neck locating Gaetano.
然后，如果找到了他，他很可能
Then, if he finds him, he's just as liable
命令他躲在自己身后
to order him to stay behind.
你说呢？
You tell me.
你是不是真的认为飞船能起飞？
Do you really think the ship will ever leave?
除非我们把这些枪弄回去，它飞不起来的
Well, it won't unless we get these phasers back.
瞧，史波克先生，他们并没害怕很长时间对吧？
Well, Mr. Spock, they didn't stay frightened very long, did they?
极不合理的反应
A most illogical reaction.
当我们展示了先进武器时，他们应该就逃跑了
When we demonstrated our superior weapons, they should have fled.
你是说他们应该尊敬我们？
You mean they should've respected us?
- 当然 - 史波克先生
- Of course. - Mr. Spock,
尊敬是一个理性过程
respect is a rational process.
你是否考虑过他们也许会有情绪化的反应，怒火中烧？
Did it ever occur to you they might react emotionally, with anger?
医生，我无法为他们的不可预见性负责
Doctor, I’m not responsible for their unpredictability.
对任何有情感的人来说
They were perfectly predictable,
他们这是完全可预测的
to anyone with feeling.
你不妨承认吧，史波克先生
You might as well admit it, Mr. Spock.
你珍爱的逻辑把他们引到了这儿
Your precious logic brought them down on us.
他们为什么还没行动？
Why haven't they done anything?
他们在研究我们，暂时是
They're studying us, for the moment.
又一个预测，史波克先生？
Another prediction, Mr. Spock?
是我的想法，博马先生
My opinion, Mr. Boma.
关好窗！
Seal the windows!
研究我们吗，史波克先生？
Studying us, Mr. Spock?
看来他们学得倒挺快
They seem to learn rather quickly.
好吧，史波克，你掌握着所有答案，现在呢？
All right, Spock, you have all the answers. What now?
博马先生，你的语气越来越充满敌意
Mr. Boma, your tone is increasingly hostile.
充满敌意的并不仅仅是我的语气，史波克先生
My tone isn't the only thing that's hostile, Mr. Spock.
真奇怪，太不合理了
Curious. Most illogical.
我厌倦了你的逻辑
And I’m sick and tired of your logic.
我们可以利用一点灵感的
We could use a little inspiration.
奇怪
Strange.
每一步我都做出了正确合理的决定
Step by step, I've made the correct and logical decisions.
仍然有两人死亡
And yet two men have died.
你还领来了我们毛茸茸的朋友
You've brought our furry friends down on us.
对，看来我的确是对他们判断错误
Yes, I do seem to have miscalculated regarding them
也没有算到你们的怨恨
and inculcated resentment on your parts.
部分的总和不可能大于总体
The sum of the parts cannot be greater than the whole.
少一点分析，多一点行动，这才是我们需要的，史波克先生
A little less analysis and more action. That's what we need, Mr. Spock.
- 还有多久，史考特先生 - 一小时，也许两小时
- How much longer, Mr. Scott? - Another hour, maybe two.
这可太久了
That won't be long enough.
医生，相位枪只能用这么快了
Doctor, a phaser can only drain so fast.
你觉得这些板子这样能撑多久？
How long do you think those plates will hold out under this?
必须得做点什么
We've gotta do something.
那你就有得忙了
You've got your hands full.
舰长日志，星历2823.1
Captain's log, stardate 2823.1.
登陆队已经踏上金牛座2号星
Our landing parties are on the surface of Taurus II,
我们仍然期盼着
and we continue to hope.
随着离子风暴渐渐散去
Instruments are only slowly returning to an operable condition
仪器慢慢地回到可操作状态
as the ion storm slowly disperses.
在舰上我们只能无助地等待
On the ship, we can only wait helplessly.
传感器区有什么消息？
What word from the Sensor Section?
上一个报告说收到了读数…
At last report they were getting readings--
我对上一个报告没兴趣，我想知道的是现在
I'm not interested in the last report. I wanna know now.
- 好的，长官 - 你还有2小时
- Yes, sir. - You have two hours
加43分钟，舰长
and 43 minutes, captain.
剩下多少时间我心知肚明，专员先生
I'm perfectly aware of how much time I have left, commissioner.
很好，但是我还是会不断提醒你的
I am delighted. However, I shall continue to remind you.
悉随尊便
You do that.
长官，传感器区域报告
Sir, Sensor Section reporting.
静电干扰仍然造成虚像
Static interference still creating false images.
估计80%不可靠
Estimates 80 percent undependable.
- 无线电通讯呢？ - 缓慢恢复中
- What about radio communication? - Clearing slowly.
还无法传送或接收
Still incapable of transmission or reception.
打算怎么办？
What do you intend to do?
干什么？我要继续搜索，一寸寸的
Do? I intend to continue the search, foot by foot, inch by inch,
如有必要甚至用烛火
by candlelight if necessary,
直到最后一刻
until the last possible moment.
如果你能不干涉我在船上的职务，我会很感激的
And if you'd keep your nose off my bridge, I'd be thankful.
船长，我确信当局会满意你所做出的努力的
I'm sure the authorities will be pleased by your diligence, captain.
但是我不确定他们是否会欣赏你
I'm not sure they'll appreciate the way you address
对一个高级专员说话的方式
a high commissioner.
菲利斯先生，我才是这里的指挥官
I'm in command here, Mr. Ferris.
是的，舰长
You are, captain.
你只剩下2小时42分钟了
For another two hours and 42 minutes.
史考特先生，飞船的电池还剩下多少？
Mr. Scott, how much power do we have left in the ship's batteries?
嗯，它们没被损坏
Well, they're in good shape,
但是，如果要想使飞船升空，电量还不足
but they won't lift us off, if that's what you're getting at.
电池能连接到飞船的外壳吗？
Will they electrify the exterior of this ship?
- 是的，史波克先生 - 好的，去做
- That they will, Mr. Spock. - All right, go.
到飞船的中央去，不要碰舱壁
Get to the centre of the ship. Don't touch the plates.
不要让自己触电了
Be sure you're insulated.
预备，史波克，好了吗？
Stand by. Are you ready, Scott?
- 好了，史波克先生 - 好的，行动吧
- Ready, Mr. Spock. - All right, go.
再来
Again.
我不能再继续了，不然会着火的
I daren't use any more, not and be sure of ignition.
史考特先生，我也认为足够了
I believe we've used enough, Mr. Scott.
我建议继续使用相位枪提供能量
I suggest you continue draining the phasers.
- 电击一定起作用了 - 暂时的
- It must have worked. - For the moment.
暂时的？
For the moment?
当他们发现他们并没有伤得很严重时，他们就会回来
The moment they discover they're not seriously hurt, they'll be back.
同时，请检查下飞船后部船箱
Meanwhile, please check the aft compartment.
看看是不是还有其他的东西能减轻飞船的重量
See if there's anything else you can unload to lighten the ship.
盖塔诺先生的遗体被找回来了
Mr. Gaetano's body is back there.
当然，遗体也要留在这里
It will, of course, have to be left behind.
- 那不能没有葬礼 - 我不建议这么做
- Not without a burial. - I wouldn't recommend it.
那些生物不会走远的
The creatures won't be far away.
史波克先生，不能没有葬礼
Not without a burial, Mr. Spock.
这会使我们的船员暴露于不必要的危险中
It would expose members of this crew to unnecessary peril.
我还是要试一试
I'll take that chance.
史波克先生，你要知道
You see, Mr. Spock,
我坚持给他们一个体面的葬礼，即使是你死在了这里
I would insist upon a decent burial, even if your body was back there.
博马先生
Mr. Boma.
我受够了这个冷酷的机器人
Well, I’m sick and tired of this machine.
够了
That's enough.
先生们
Gentlemen.
好吧，博马先生，你要的葬礼可以有
All right, Mr. Boma, you'll have your burial.
只要那些生物不阻止你
Provided the creatures will permit it.
寇克舰长，第二登陆队被传送回星舰上了
Captain Kirk, landing party number two is being beamed back aboard ship.
他们出了意外，一死两伤
They have casualties. One dead, two injured.
可视电话连线克洛伊兹上尉
Put Lieutenant Kelowitz on visual.
克洛伊兹，船长
Kelowitz, captain.
报告你的遭遇
Your report.
船长，我们被袭击了
We were attacked, captain.
对方是浑身长毛的巨大生物
Huge, furry creatures.
我查看了星际人类学
I checked with Astral Anthropology
他们被确定为480-G，类人猿
and they're order 480-G, anthropoid,
和在汉森星球发现的生命形式相似
similar to life forms discovered on Hansen's Planet,
但是要大得多，10到12英尺高
but much larger. Ten, 12 feet in height.
你的伤亡情况呢？
Your casualties?
在我们发现他们在附近之前
Well, Ensign O'Neill got a spear through the body
奥尼尔少尉就被一柄长矛刺穿了
before we even knew they were around.
今村上尉胳膊脱臼了
Lieutenant Immamura has a dislocated shoulder
身上还有几道重伤口，但并无大碍
and severe lacerations, but he'll make it all right.
船长，那个地方到处都是那种生物
Captain, the creatures are all over the place.
如果伽利略号降落到了哪个星球，我--
If the Galileo is down on that planet, I--
谢谢你，上尉
Thank you, lieutenant.
你最好也去医务室报到
You better report to Sickbay yourself.
是的，船长
Aye, captain.
寇克船长
Captain Kirk,
如果你看你的计时器，你会发现现在已经是2823.8了
if you check your chronometer, you'll see it is 2823.8.
- 你的时间到了 - 但是他们还没有返回
- Your time is up. - But they're still out there.
在新巴黎的瘟疫受害者也是一样
So are the plague victims on New Paris.
抱歉，舰长，我现在依据银河系第15号…
I'm sorry, captain. I now assume authority granted me
紧急情况处理程序赋予我的权利
under title 15, galactic emergency procedures.
命令你立刻终止搜索
And I order you to abandon search.
哥伦布号还没有返航
The Columbus hasn't returned yet.
我还有两只搜索部队在外面
I still have two search parties out.
船长，你是在拖延，你收到了命令
You're procrastinating, captain. You have your orders.
召回你的搜索部队，然后立即向玛克斯3号出发
Recall your search parties and proceed to Makus III immediately.
- 上尉 - 是的，长官？
- Lieutenant. - Yes, sir?
命令传送室立刻
Order the Transporter Room to immediately beam up
将两支在地面的搜索部队传送回星舰
the two search parties from the surface.
试着联系哥伦布号
Attempt to contact the Columbus.
长官，我现在和他们保持着部分联系
I'm in partial contact with them now, sir.
让他们立即返回，苏鲁先生
Then have them return immediately. Mr. Sulu?
准备终止搜索
Prepare to abandon search.
将星舰驶向玛克斯3号
Set course for Makus III.
船长日志，补充
Captain's log, supplement.
搜索部队已经回到船上了
The search parties have returned to the ship
哥伦布号也在返回
and the Columbus is on its way back.
我被迫终止了搜索
I have been compelled to abandon the search.
船长，探测部门说传送器恢复工作了
Captain, Sensor Section says the beams are working again.
- 其他系统怎么样？ - 还没有，长官，干扰太多了
- What about the other systems? - No, sir. Too much interference.
船长，已经将航向设定为玛克斯3号
Captain, course set for Makus III.
苏鲁先生，准备出发
Stand ready, Mr. Sulu.
还要多长时间，哥伦布号才能登舰？
How long before the Columbus comes onboard?
长官，23分钟
Twenty-three minutes, sir.
23分钟
Twenty-three minutes.
进取号，这是伽利略号，请回答，进取号
Enterprise, this is Galileo. Come in, please. Enterprise.
长官，什么也没有，都是离子干扰
Nothing, sir. Just ionic interference.
修好了
That's it.
飞船负重怎么样？
How about weight?
如果已经去除所有不必要的重量 或许能达到绕地飞行的速度
If we shed every ounce, we might be able to achieve orbit.
那我们能维持多久？
And how long can we hold it?
最多几个小时
A few hours, no longer.
但是，如果时间计算准确，我们能脱离绕地轨道
But if we time it right, we can cut out of orbit
节约足够能量做一次可控着陆
and save enough fuel for a controlled re-entry.
再回到这地方？这不是个好主意
To land here again? Not a very attractive possibility.
史波克先生，我们的选择不多
We have very few alternatives, Mr. Spock.
麦考伊医生，博马先生
Dr. McCoy, Mr. Boma.
史考特，什么时候能起飞？
When can we lift off, Scott?
如果飞船负重适宜，或许8分钟后
Maybe eight minutes, if the weight's right.
先生们，飞船10分钟后准时起飞
Gentlemen, ship will lift off in exactly ten minutes.
你们可以在此期间埋葬盖塔诺先生
You have that long to bury Mr. Gaetano.
现在，外面看起来很安全，至少暂时是那样
Now, it appears to be clear outside, at least for the moment.
我会协助你们的，快点
I'll assist you. Hurry.
长官，哥伦布号已经登舰，飞行舱门已经关闭了
The Columbus is aboard, sir. The flight hatch is closed.
传送室报告说，最后一支地面部队
Transporter Room reports last of the landing parties
已经安全回到船上
have beamed safely up.
所有系统报告可以进行曲速航行
All systems report secured for warp factors.
苏鲁先生，向玛克斯3号出发
Mr. Sulu, proceed on course for Makus III,
用空间航行正常速度
at space-normal speed.
- 空间航行正常速度？ - 是的
- Space-normal, sir? - Those are my orders.
乌乎拉上尉，命令所有的传感器部门
Lieutenant Uhura, order all Sensor Sections
以100%功率向后方发射传感器信号
to direct beams aft, full function,
长期执行，直到进一步命令
continuous operation, until further orders.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
快上船！立刻起飞！
Get on the ship! Immediate liftoff!
不，回去！起飞！
No, go back! Lift off!
快回去！不！
Go back! No!
好了，好了！出发！出发！
All right. All right. Go, go, go!
出发！
Go!
- 出发，史考特 - 好的，长官
- Go, Scott. - Aye, aye, sir.
我让你们起飞的
I told you to lift off.
别傻了，史波克先生，我们不会把你留在外面的
Don't be a fool, Mr. Spock. We couldn't leave you out there.
- 史考特，赶紧起飞 - 我已经发动飞船了，但还是没起飞
- Get us off, Scott. - We should be moving, but we're not.
正是如此，史考特先生，他们好像要把我们拉下来
Quite right, Mr. Scott. They seem to be holding us down.
所有系统运转，但还是不能起飞
All systems are go, but we're not moving.
- 你在干什么？ - 那是助推器
- What are you doing? - Our boosters.
- 这样我们就不能保持绕地飞行了 - 那你更愿意待在这里了？
- We'll never be able to hold orbit. - Would you rather stay here?
好吧，史波克先生
Go, Mr. Spock.
- 飞船在动！ - 他们放手了
- We're moving! - They let go!
或者跌下去了
Or fell off.
我提醒你们，我们尚未到达绕地轨道
I remind you, we have yet to achieve orbit,
我们也不能坚持很长时间
nor can we maintain it long.
一小时后，我们或许会回到我们出发的地方
An hour from now, we may be right back where we started from.
先生们，带我上飞船或许
Gentlemen, by coming after me, you may well have destroyed
毁掉了你们原本就渺茫的生还机会
what slim chance you had for your survival.
你们本该把我留在那里，那才最符合逻辑
The logical thing for you to have done was to have left me behind.
史波克先生，请提醒我告知你
Mr. Spock, remind me to tell you
我受够了你该死的逻辑
that I'm sick and tired of your logic.
这是最不合逻辑的观点
That is a most illogical attitude.
史考特先生，一分钟后到达绕地轨道
Orbit in one minute, Mr. Scott.
- 燃料状态？ - 15磅psi
- Fuel status? - Fifteen pounds psi.
长官，大约足够绕地一圈
Approximately enough for one orbit, sir.
之后呢？
After that?
刚才按下推进器已将我们软着陆的机会毁掉了
Tapping our boosters ended our last chance for a soft landing.
我是说飞船会燃尽？
You mean a burn-up?
衰减轨道飞行一般都是如此结局
That is the usual end of a decaying orbit.
我不想死在这里
I don't wanna die up here.
这种死法要比在那颗星球上的死法
Infinitely preferable to the kind of death we'd be granted
要好得多，我觉得
on the planet's surface, I should think.
我羡慕你那做出如此理智选择的能力
I admire your ability to make so measured a choice.
史波克先生，你那时说过，总会有其他选择的
Mr. Spock, you said a while ago that there were always alternatives.
我说过吗？
Did I?
我或许弄错了
I may have been mistaken.
好吧，有生之年居然能听到你说这句话
Well, at least I lived long enough to hear that.
我们还能怎么做？
Is there anything we can do?
现在进取号一定已经驶向玛克斯3号了
The Enterprise is surely on course for Makus III by now.
就我个人来说，我不相信奇迹
I for one do not believe in angels.
好了，史波克先生，第一次指挥就这种结局
Well, Mr. Spock, so ends your first command.
是的
Yes.
我的第一次指挥
My first command.
史波克先生，到达绕地轨道高度
Orbit attitude, Mr. Spock.
以我们现有的燃料，能坚持45分钟
With our present fuel, that gives us about 45 minutes.
伽利略号呼叫进取号
Galileo to Enterprise.
伽利略号呼叫进取号，请回答
Galileo to Enterprise. Come in, please.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
- 怎么回事？ - 他排出并点燃了燃料
- What happened? - He jettisoned the fuel and ignited it.
这些燃料是用来维持绕地轨道的
We need that fuel to maintain orbit.
- 你疯了吗？ - 或许吧，博马先生
- Are you out of your mind? - Perhaps, Mr. Boma.
史考特，我们现在还能坚持多久？
How long have we got now, Scotty?
只要燃料一耗尽，就会进入衰减轨道
Well, the orbit will start decaying as soon as the fuel is exhausted.
大约6分钟
Say, six minutes.
- 大气与重力部门报告情况 - 大气与重力部门正在稳定
- A-G Section acknowledging. - A-G Section is stabilising.
大气和重力正在稳定
Atmosphere and gravity are stabilising.
所有人员向船长报告，处于三级状态
All decks to the captain, condition three.
将前方情形传送到指挥部，报告状况，全体戒备
Forward scanner to Bridge. Status report. Section on alert.
船长，屏幕上有情况，在金牛座2号
Captain, something there on the screen, at Taurus II.
传感器部门，那是流星吗？
Sensors. A meteorite?
不，运动轨迹呈弧线
No, it's holding a lateral line.
它又来了
There it is again.
船长，它运行很稳定
Holding steady, captain.
苏鲁先生，调转180度
A hundred and eighty degrees about, Mr. Sulu.
乌乎拉上尉，联系传送室
Lieutenant Uhura, contact Transporter Room.
启动所有传送器，全速发射
All beams ready. Full normal speed.
求救信号？
A distress signal?
就像是发射了一枚曳光弹
It's like sending up a flare.
史波克先生，这是场豪赌，或许这是值得的
Mr. Spock, that was a good gamble. Perhaps it was worth it.
没有人会看到的
No one out there to see it.
史波克先生，轨道在衰减
Orbit decaying, Mr. Spock.
十秒钟进入大气层
Ten seconds to atmosphere.
史波克先生，这或许是你的最后一次行动了
It may be the last action you'll ever take, Mr. Spock.
但这完全是人类的方式
But it was all human.
完全不合逻辑
Totally illogical.
根本没有机会
There was no chance.
我就是这个意思
That's exactly what I mean.
越来越热了
It's getting hot.
传输器锁定目标了，长官
Transporters locked in, sir.
启动传送器
Activate beams.
船长，不管那是什么
Whatever it was, captain,
它刚刚在大气里燃尽了
it just burned up in the atmosphere.
船长，传送室接收到5个人
Captain, Transporter Room just beamed up five persons.
平安无恙
Alive and well.
苏鲁先生
Mr. Sulu,
继续向玛克斯3号方向航行
proceed on course to Makus III.
- 以一级曲速 - 是的，长官
- Ahead warp factor 1. - Aye, aye, sir.
一级曲速
Warp factor 1.
- 史波克先生 - 船长
- Mr. Spock. - Captain.
这件事里我对某些东西非常不理解
There's really something I don't understand about all this,
当然，你或许能给出合乎逻辑的解释
and maybe you can explain it to me, logically, of course.
当你排出燃料并点燃的时候
When you jettisoned the fuel and you ignited it,
你也知道几乎没有被发现的可能
you knew that there was virtually no chance of it being seen,
但是你还是那样做了，我认为那是
and yet you did it anyhow. Now, that would seem to me
- 一种绝望的行为 - 船长，非常正确
- to be an act of desperation. - Quite correct, captain.
我们也知道，我确信医生也会同意我的
Now, we all know, and I’m sure the doctor will agree with me,
绝望是一种高度情绪化的状态
that desperation is a highly emotional state of mind.
你那众所周知的逻辑思维该怎么解释呢？
How does your well-known logic explain that?
船长，这很简单
Quite simply, captain.
我从各个方面考虑当时的问题
I examined the problem from all angles,
基本上都无望
and it was plainly hopeless.
逻辑告诉我，在那种情况下
Logic informed me that under the circumstances,
唯一可能的行动就是绝望的行动
the only possible action would have to be one of desperation.
逻辑的决定，逻辑地作出了
Logical decision, logically arrived at.
我明白了，你的理由是当时该来一次
I see. You mean you reasoned that it was time
情绪的爆发
for an emotional outburst.
嗯，船长，我认为不该那么说
Well, I wouldn't put it in exactly those terms, captain,
但那些的确都是事实
but those are essentially the facts.
你还是不承认在你生命中第一次
You're not going to admit that for the first time in your life,
做了一件完全就是人类的、情绪化的事？
you committed a purely human, emotional act?
是的，长官
No, sir.
史波克先生，你真是一个顽固的家伙
Mr. Spock, you're a stubborn man.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
本集结束
谢谢观赏
TLF字幕组欢迎你，欢迎有志之士加入
TLF中文字幕站http://tlfsubs.eastgame.org/